Earlier, we looked at the relationship between
之前我们用散点图探讨了
engine size and fuel efficiency using a scatter plot.
发动机排量大小和燃油效率之间的相关性
I've added some jitter and transparency to see where the main bulk of the data lies.
这里我设置了抖动和透明度 以便观察数据的主体位置
We can also plot this data as a heat map or a 2D histogram.
我们也可以把这些数据绘制成热图 也就是一种二维直方图
The simplest way of going about this is by using matplotlib's hist2d function.
为此 最简单的办法就是用 matplotlib 的函数 hist2d
I'm also adding a color bar function call so that a legend
我还调用了 colorbar 函数
associating the counts to colors is placed adjacent to the plot.
这样图表旁就会有与数量统计相对应的颜色图例了
Similar to the univariate hist function,
和单变量的 hist 函数一样
by default each dimension is split into
这个函数默认将每个维度分成十组
10 bins and the number of points in each rectangular bin is counted up.
并对各矩形组里的数据点进行计数统计
Each count is associated with a color.
每个统计值都对应一种颜色
In this default matplotlib color palette called for viridis,
在 matplotlib 默认的这个色板 viridis 中
higher count skew yellow and bright,
统计值越高 颜色越偏黄 亮度也越高
lower counts darker and purple.
统计值越低 颜色越偏紫 亮度也越低
We can still see the main trend we saw before but we can certainly do better.
这样我们还是能找出主体趋势 但我们能做的远不止如此
First, let's set a minimum bound of counts before a rectangular area can be plotted.
首先 在矩形区域绘制出来之前 设置统计值下限
By setting cmin to a value such as zero point five,
假如设 cmin 的值为 0.5
any bin with no counts will return as not a number and not get colored in.
任何没有统计值的组会返回为 nan 因而不会得到颜色填充
Since white now represents zero,
由于这里白色表示 0
I should choose a reversed color palette where
所以我要选一个相反的色板
darker colors are associated with higher values.
用亮度低的颜色表示高数值
I'll set the cmap variable to viridis_r,
因此 我设变量 cmap 为 viridis_r
with the underscore r indicating a reversed color map.
其中 _r 表示色板的颜色反转
There's a ton of built-in color maps
你可以在官方文档中
compatible with matplotlib that can be found in the documentation.
找到大量与 matplotlib 兼容的内置色板
I'll defer a deeper discussion of color in general until later in the course.
课程稍后会进一步介绍颜色这方面的内容
Finally, let's change the bins.
最后 修改分组
We can provide hist2d's bins parameter with a list of
我们可以为函数 hist2d 的参数 bins 提供一个列表
two hists specifying the bin edges for the x and y axis in that order.
按顺序指明 x 轴和 y 轴的组边界
After looking at the descriptive statistics for my two variables,
我看了下两个变量的描述性统计数据
I've decided to go with bin sizes of zero point three for displacement,
决定设排量的组距为 0.3
and three for the fuel efficiency.
设燃油效率的组距为 3
I'll use NumPy's arange function to assign the bin edges to
用 NumPy 的函数 arange 把组边界赋给
my bins_x and bins_y variables,
变量 bins_x 和 bins_y
and then generate the revised plot.
修改完毕 生成图表
We can see from the plot, two areas of high frequency in
由图可知 数据有两个高频区域
the middle of the negative trend between fuel efficiency and engine size
其中燃油效率和发动机排量大小呈负相关趋势